And welcome to continuing our journey with Hrag.
Hrag와 여정을 계속하는 걸 환영해요
And today it's time to unveil Liang Chen.
오늘 량천을 공개할 거예요
So first, a quick reminder of what you can already do when it comes to Hrag.
먼저 Hrag와 관련해 여러분이 이미 할 수 있는 걸 간단히 상기시켜 드리죠
So we last time talked about the simple idea behind Hrag.
지난 시간에는 Hrag의 단순한 아이디어를 다뤘죠
Just the idea that you could retrieve relevant contexts and include that in the prompt.
관련 맥락을 검색해 그걸 프롬프트 안에 포함할 수 있다는 생각이죠
And then we talked a bit about vectors and how text can be mapped to a vector that represents its meaning.
벡터에 대해서도 비트 했죠 텍스트가 의미를 나타내는 벡터에 매핑되는 방법도요
And you can use these vectors to try to be more intelligent about how you select relevant context for
이 벡터를 이용해 프롬프트에 대한 관련 컨텍스트를 어떻게 선택할지 보다 영리해지려고 노력할
the prompt.
수 있어요
So today we're going to talk about Lang chain.
오늘은 랑 체인에 대해 얘기해 보죠
I'm going to describe the framework and its pros and cons.
프레임워크와 장단점을 설명해 드릴게요
We're going to use Lang chain to read in our knowledge base and to divide it into chunks of relevant
랭 체인을 이용해 지식 기반에서 읽고 관련 정보 덩어리로 나눌 겁니다 나중에
information, which later will be putting in a vector database and retrieving.
벡터 데이터베이스에 넣고 검색할 정보죠
So here is the backstory to Lang Chain.
랑 체인의 배경은 이거예요
It's a relatively recent framework.
비교적 최근에 만들어진 프레임워크예요
It was created in late 2022, and its main goal is to allow allow people to build LLM applications quickly,
2022년 말에 만들어진 이 제품의 주요 목표는 사람들이 LLM 애플리케이션을 빠르게 구축할 수 있게 하는 것입니다
stitching together different bits of functionality into a sort of chain of processing.
다양한 기능성 비트를 함께 엮어서 일종의 프로세싱 사슬을 만드는 것이죠
It actually has its own language, its own declarative language called Lang Chain Expression Language.
그들만의 언어가 있어요 선언어죠 랭 체인 표현 언어예요
LCL and we're not going to be using that.
LCL이요 이건 사용하지 않을 거예요
Particularly I am going to show you some of it, but there are simpler ways to use lang chain just by
특히 제가 보여드릴 텐데요 파이썬 코드로 랑 체인을 이용하는 더
using Python code.
간단한 방법도 있어요
So what are the pros and cons?
장단점이 뭐가 있죠?
So it does hugely simplify creating applications to do common things like assistance and Rag.
어시스트나 Rag 같은 일반적인 작업을 위해 응용 프로그램 생성을 크게 단순화하죠
As we will see, it's going to literally be a few lines of code.
보다시피 코드 몇 줄로 끝날 거예요
So it gives you very quick time to market.
그래서 판매 시간을 단축할 수 있죠
There's nothing particularly magical about something like rag.
천 조각 같은 건 마법과는 거리가 멀어요
We could do it the brute force way, by looking up in a vector database by adding to the prompt.
브루트 포스 방식으로 할 수도 있습니다 벡터 데이터베이스를 찾아 프롬프트에 추가하는 거죠
Lang chain just standardizes and simplifies and makes it all easier and quicker.
랭 체인은 모든 걸 쉽고 빠르게 표준화하고 단순화해요
It's also a useful wrapper code around common models, so that you can write your code once and then
일반적인 모델에 관한 유용한 래퍼 코드이기도 하죠 코드를 한 번 작성하고 OpenAI나 클로드
switch in different models like OpenAI or Claude, and not have to deal with the slight differences
같은 다른 모델을 전환할 수 있어요 API에서의 약간의 차이를 처리할
in the API, which you can imagine is just sort of convenient.
필요가 없죠 좀 편리하다고 생각하실 거예요
You can imagine that we could do that ourselves.
우리가 직접 할 수 있다고 상상해 보세요
We could write a little wrapper function, much as we did when we were using Gradio to call two different
래퍼 함수를 쓸 수 있어요 그래디오를 이용해 두 개의 다른 llm을 호출했을 때처럼요
And that's essentially what Lang Chain has done.
랑 체인이 한 일이 바로 그거예요
They've built wrappers around the common APIs.
일반적인 API 주변에 래퍼를 구축했어요
It has to be said, as the APIs for LMS has matured, as they've become increasingly similar, and as
LMS에 대한 API가 성숙해지면서 점점 유사해지고 이를 위한 일종의
the sort of code scripts out there for doing this become more and more widespread, there is less of
코드 스크립트가 점점 광범위해지면서 랭 체인 같은 기본 프레임워크에
a need for an underlying framework like Lang Chain than there was perhaps a year ago.
대한 필요성이 적어도 1년 전보다는 줄었어요
So the need is decreased a bit.
비트가 좀 줄었네요
There's a lot of people that are rolling their own in terms of building their own pipelines for things
래그 파이프라인을 직접 만드는 사람이 많아요 래그 파이프라인을
like Rag, and you'll see how easy it would be to do that too.
직접 만드는 거죠 얼마나 쉬운지 보실 거예요
But Lang Chain still gives you a tremendous head start.
랭 체인에서 출발하면 유리할 거예요 HMSW HMSW HMSW
And so it's very useful framework as you will see today.
오늘날 보시게 될 아주 유용한 프레임워크죠
So what we're going to do is we're going to use Lang chain to load in our knowledge base.
그래서 랭 체인을 이용해 지식 기반을 로드할 거예요
We're first going to read all of the documents stored in the folders using some some tooling.
먼저 폴더에 저장된 모든 문서를 읽겠습니다 일부 도구를 이용해서요
We're then going to add metadata to the documents to say what kind of document it is, which is going
그런 다음 문서에 메타데이터를 추가해 어떤 종류의 문서인지 알려줍니다 나중에
to be useful for us later.
유용할 거예요
And then we're going to use Lang chain to break the documents down into useful chunks, chunks which
그런 다음 랭 체인을 이용해 문서를 유용한 청크로 나눌 겁니다 함께 잘 어우러진
represent text that belongs nicely together and will be ready to be vectorized and put in our database.
텍스트를 나타내는 청크요 벡터화되어 데이터베이스에 들어갈 준비가 된 거죠
So with that, let's head back to JupyterLab.
그럼 이제 주피터랩으로 돌아가죠 HOLO